Alberto Roque Carrizo Fernández

roquec.com · github.com/roquec · linkedin.com/in/roquec · contact@roquec.com · Gijón, Spain

Introduction

I am an experienced software engineer with a pragmatic approach, valuing simplicity in solutions. Highly independent and adept at self-learning, I seek opportunities to deliver genuine value to clients and society. Aside from coding I also share my insights and experiences through tech articles on my personal blog.

Skills

.NET C# Azure SQL Elasticsearch Redis Git Docker Microservices GraphQL Powershell JavaScript SASS

Experience

Sep 2018 - May 2022 · Senior Backend Engineer at NEOCLES (B2B e-commerce platform for fashion)

- Designed and built high-performance e-commerce APIs for thousands of concurrent users.
- Managed releases and maintenance for 5 segregated client production environments.
- Developed backend services receiving 10M+ import messages daily from external systems.
- · Led upgrade and configuration of 30+ Elasticsearch servers, saving thousands of euros monthly.
- Worked directly with clients conducting fit-gap analyses to integrate new services and features.
- Used .NET C# SQL Elasticsearch Azure Redis Docker AKS Service Bus.

Jan 2017- Sep 2018 · Full-stack Developer at INVESTEL (fleet management system)

- Led development of an AngularJS management application for internal use.
- · Worked with designer on implementation of new Angular frontend for existing application.
- Evolved into a full-stack developer role, addressing bugs and implementing new features in the backend.
- Implemented and documented OAuth service for external client authentication.
- Used AngularJS C# SQL .NET Framework Redis Mercurial.

Projects

Sep 2022 - Present · Ship Navigation Application · Winui3 C# .NET

- Designed and build Windows desktop application based on clients requirements.
- Integrated with Automatic Identification Systems (AIS) via serial port connection.

Mar 2023 - Oct 2023 · Portfolio Website: roquec.com · Jekyll JavaScript SASS

- Developed custom SASS styling to imitate Visual Studio Code look.
- Created JavaScript solution for smooth SPA-like state through page navigations.
- · Automated deployments, Lighthouse testing and reporting using GitHub Actions and Powershell.

Education

Nov 2019 · Microsoft Exam AZ-400 Designing and Implementing Microsoft DevOps Solutions.

2011 - 2016 · Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering from University of Oviedo, Spain.

Languages

English (Full professional proficiency) and Spanish (Native).